A Guide to the John Hart Collection of Confederate Letters and Receipts, 1860-1868
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
John Hart Collection of Confederate Letters and Receipts, 1860-1868
Library of Virginia
20234
19 leaves and 39 pages
John Hart
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from John Hart, 21 August 1930
Biographical Information
John Hart was a collector of papers concerning Virginia history.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1860-1868, collected by John Hart consisting of letters, petitions, affidavits, receipts, and treasury certificates and warrants. Nine items relate to Timothy White (d. 1864) of Company D, 61st Virginia Infantry, including charges of desertion by Lieutenant V. A. Haynes; petition by C. Y. Savage of Petersburg, Virginia, to army authorities for return of money he paid to White in a fraudulent sale of slaves in Gates County, North Carolina; letters and affidavits from F. H. Cobb, James A. Crop, Alexander Donnan (1813-1892), and William Robertson regarding Savage's claim against White and White's release from jail; letters from Major General Samuel Gibbs French (1818-1910) to Judge William T. Joynes (1817-1874) and to Major E. Branch concerning Savage's petition and money found on White at the time of his arrest; and letters from Captain John A. Gayle, Company C, 16th Virginia, to William T. Joynes concerning Savage and White, and to David May (ca. 1795-1870) asking for May's help in protecting the interests of the deceased White. Nine items consist of seven receipts to Dr. John C. Bragg of Petersburg, Amelia County, and Nottoway Counties, Virginia, for coal, hogs, and bacon supplied to the Confederate Army; receipts for payment of his taxes with corn, wheat, molasses, potatoes, peas and beans; and a receipt from J.R. Anderson and Co. for delivery of iron to Dr. J.C. Bragg; two receipts to the estate of William A. Bragg of Nottoway County for payment of taxes with corn.
Collection also includes three warants on the treasurer of the Confederate States, numbers 2340 ($200), 2660 ($1,400), 2676 ($1,400), from James G. Paxton of Lynchburg, Virginia, to M. E. Price, assistant quartermaster, C.S.A. Three items relate to Green Hill of Petersburg, including a certificate for payment of $300 for Confederate bonds and two receipts for payment of taxes on property in Dinwiddie County, Virginia, by Hill's estate. Three certificates from the depository of the Confederate States of America for issue of bonds to B. B. Arnold, Baughan and Richards located in southwestern Richmond, and A. W. Daley of Augusta County, Georgia. Letter, 30 October 1860, from James T. Ames, agent, per George Ames, of Ames Manufacturing Company, Chicopee, Massachusetts, to John P. May (1829-1862) of Petersburg concerning the price and availability of swords. Letter, 10 September 1861, from John Gibson of Richmond, Virginia to David May of Petersburg regarding Susan, a runaway slave. Letter, 9 January and 8 February 1862, from David May to John J. Blackstone of Accomack County, Virginia, concerning "Mt. Custis," the estate of Thomas Henry Bayly (1809-1856), and includes comments and suggestions about the letter from Mr. Perkins and from Richard Henry Baker, Jr (1826-1911). Letter, 6 November 1865, from Captain Stuart Burns, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands, to David May informing May he is appointed Petersburg's representative for the bureau. Letter, 12 January 1868, from William Moore to Henry A. Wise (1806-1876) concerning payment of a bill.
Arrangement
Chronological
Contents List
- Letter, 30 October 1860, James L. Ames, agent, per George Ames, Ames Manufacturing Company, Chicopee, Massachusetts, to John P. May, Petersburg, Virginia, concerning the cost and workmanship of the company's swords., 2 p.
- Letter, 10 September 1861, from John Gibson, Richmond, Virginia, to David May, Petersburg, regarding Susan, a runaway slave., 1 leaf.
- Letter, 9 January 1862, David May, Petersburg, to John J. Blackstone, [Accomack County, Virginia], concerning Mt. Custis, the estate of Thomas Henry Bayly. Includes a postscript dated 8 February by May, amendments suggested by Mr. Perkins, and a memorandum by Richard Henry Baker, Jr., 4 p.
- Charges and specifications, 1863, preferred against Private Timothy White, 61st Virginia Infantry, Company D by Lieutenant V. A. Haynes. White was charged with desertion., 2 p.
- Petition, 26 March 1863, C. Y. Savage, Petersburg, to the general commanding post at Petersburg requesting the return to him of money taken from Timothy White who had been arrested for desertion. Savage had purchased slaves from White. Also includes affidavits by James A. Crop and F. H. Cobb, both of Petersburg., 2 leaves and 2 p.
- Letter, 8 October 1863, from Alexander Donnan, Petersburg, to Major General S. G. French, C.S.A., regarding the petition of C. Y. Savage., 2 p.
- Letter, 8 October 1863, from William Robertson, Petersburg, to General S. G. French concerning the petition of C. Y. Savage and containing affidavits., 1 leaf and 2 p.
- Letter, 20 October 1863, from Major General S. G. French, Enterprise, Mississippi, to Judge William T. Joynes, Petersburg, commenting on the petition of C. Y. Savage and an order that certain money be paid to him., 3 p.
- Receipt, 17 November 1863, from W. W. Lanier, depot agent South Side Rail Road Company, Petersburg, to Doctor John C. Bragg, for shipment of coal., 1 leaf.
- Receipt, 9 December 1863, from W. H. Hallowell, depot agent, by D. Hudgings, South Side Rail Road Company, Burkeville, Virginia, to Dr. John C. Bragg, Amelia County, Virginia, for transportation of hogs., 1 leaf.
- Letter, 18 January 1864, from Major General Samuel Gibbs French, C.S.A., Meridian, Mississippi, to Major E. B. Branch, Petersburg, authorizing Branch to deliver certain money to Timothy White., 1 leaf.
- Letter, 26 January 1864, from Captain John H. Gayle, 16th Virginia Infantry, Company C, to Judge William T. Joynes regarding the claim of C. Y. Savage., 2 p.
- Letter, 9 March 1864, from Captain John H. Gayle, 16th Virginia Infantry, Company C, to Judge William T. Joynes commenting on the claim of C. Y. Savage., 2 p.
- Receipt, 12 March 1864, from Captain Louis L. Marks by B. B. Smithy, Quartermaster's Department, C.S.A., to Dr. John C. Bragg for bacon., 1 leaf.
- Certificate No. 1584, 15 March 1864, Daniel Dulsen[?], Depository, C.S.A., Petersburg, to Green Hill stating that Hill has paid $300 and is to be issued bonds., 1 leaf.
- Letter, 16 March 1864, from Captain John H. Gayle, 16th Virginia Infantry, Company C, to David May requesting assistance in "protecting the interests of Timothy White, deceased.", 2 p.
- Certificate No. 1980, 29 March 1864, Depository, C.S.A., to B. B. Arnold stating that Arnold has paid $500 and is to be issued bonds. Subsequent assignments are noted., 2 p.
- Certificate No. 1284, 6 June 1864, F. B. Hurt, Depository, Abingdon, Virginia, to Baughman and Richards, [Richmond?], stating that Baughman and Richards has paid $500 and is to be issued bonds. Subsequent assignments are noted., 2 p.
- Certificate No. 293, 21 June 1864, M. Hatch, Depository, C.S.A., Augusta, Georgia, to A. W. Daley stating that Daley has paid $500 and is to be issued bonds. Subsequent assignments are noted., 2 p.
- Receipt, 2 August 1864, from Major C. L. Randolph, Quartermaster's Department, to Dr. John C. Bragg, Nottoway County, Virginia, for payment of taxes in corn., 1 leaf.
- Receipt, 7 September 1864, from Captain L. L. Marks by R. T. Jeter, Quartermaster's Department, to John C. Bragg for payment of taxes in wheat., l leaf.
- Receipt, 26 October 1864, from Captain J. J. Young, Quartermaster's Department, to the estate of William A. Bragg for payment of taxes in corn., 1 leaf.
- Receipt, 17 December 1864, from W. H. Cardozo, depot agent, Richmond and Danville Railroad Company to J. R. Anderson and Company for transportation of iron to Jetersville, [Virginia]., 1 leaf.
- Receipt, 20 January 1865, from the Quartermaster's Department to Dr. John C. Bragg, Nottoway County, for payment of taxes in various products., 1 leaf.
- Receipt, 2 February 1865, from the Quartermaster's Department to the estate of W. A. Bragg, Nottoway County, for payment of taxes in corn., 1 leaf.
- Warrant No. 2340, 11 March 1865, James G. Paxton, Lynchburg, Virginia, to M. E. Price, assitant quartermaster, Quartermaster's Department, C.S.A. Warrant on the Treasurer of the Confederate States for $200., 1 leaf.
- Warrant No. 2660, 11 March 1865, James G. Paxton, Lynchburg, Virginia, to M. E. Price, assitant quartermaster, Quartermaster's Department, C.S.A. Warrant on the Treasurer of the Confederate States for $1,400., 1 leaf.
- Warrant No. 2676, 11 March 1865, James G. Paxton, Lynchburg, Virginia, to M. E. Price, assitant quartermaster, Quartermaster's Department, C.S.A. Warrant on the Treasurer of the Confederate States for $1,400., 1 leaf.
- Letter, 6 November 1865, from Captain Stuart Burns, Office of the Superintendent, Second District, Bureau of Refugees, Freedmen, and Abandoned Lands, Petersburg, to David May, informing May he has been chosen as a representative of the commission "to adjudicate in all claims or cases of difficulty arising between Whites and Freedmen, or between Negroes themselves.", 1 leaf.
- Receipt, 4 April 1866, from A. Watson, Petersburg, to estate of G. Hill for payment of United States direct taxes on land in Dinwiddie County., 1 leaf.
- Receipt, 13 April 1866, from A. Watson, Petersburg, to R. Hill for payment of United States direct taxes on land in Dinwiddie County., 1 leaf.
- Letter, 12 January 1868, from William Moore to Henry A. Wise requesting information concerning collection of a bill., 1 leaf.